Guide to the George Eliot and George Henry Lewes Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section I. Letters by GEORGE ELIOT to:, 1877 Feb 13
  - Liggins, Joseph (Box 4)
    See: GE's letter to The Times for letters about his supposed authorship of Scenes of Clerical Life, etc.
  - Macmillan, Alexander, 1815-1896, 1874 Nov 10 (Box 4)
  - Main, Alexander, 1841-1918, 1871 Aug 9
    - ----, 1872 Nov 4 (Box 4)
  - Malleson, Elizabeth (Whitehead), 1863 Nov 15 (Box 4)
  - 1828-1916, (Mrs. Frank Rodbard, 1864 Dec 25 (Box 4)
  - Malleson), 1872 Dec 19
    - ----, 1880 Feb 3 (Box 4)
  - Meredith, Louisa Anne (Twamley), 1878 Nov 7 (Box 4)
  - (Mrs. Charles Meredith) (Box 4)
  - Otter, Emily Helen (Cross), 1848-1907 (Box 4)
    See: Cross, Emily Helen (Mrs. Francis Otter)
  - Pears, Elizabeth (Bray) (Mrs. Abijah Hill Pears)
    - Copy by S. S. Hennell, [1842 Jan 28] (Box 4)
      Tinker 951
    - Copy by S. S. Hennell, [1842 Mar 31] (Box 4)
      Tinker 952
    - Copy by S. S. Hennell, 1849 May 10 (Box 4)
      Tinker 953
  - Peirce, Melusina (Fay) (Mrs. Charles Sanders Peirce), 1866 Sep 14 (Box 4)
  - Pigott, E.F.S.
    - Postscript to letter by GHL (Section II), 1858 Jul 20 (Box 4)
  - Ralston, William Ralston Shedden, 1828-1889, 1868 Oct 11 (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, Frances (Mrs. John Russell), 1873 Dec 30 (Box 4)
  - Senior, Jane Elizabeth (Hughes) (Mrs. Nassau Senior)
    - Copy in an unidentified hand, [1867 May 22] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1869 Sep 9 (Box 5)
    - Copy in an unidentified hand, 1870 Mar 13 (Box 5)
    - Copy in an unidentified hand, 1872 Jul 1 (Box 5)
    - Copy in an unidentified hand, 1873 Jan 24 (Box 5)
  - Sibree, Jahn, 1823-1909
    - copy, [1848 Feb 11] (Box 5)
    - copy, [1848 Feb?] (Box 5)
    - copy, [1848 Mar 8] (Box 5)
    - copy, [1848 May 14?] (Box 5)
  - Siebold, Antonie von (Mrs. Karl Theodor Ernst von Siebold), 1861 Aug 26
    - ----, [1871 Jun] (Box 5)
  - Simpson, George, 1868 Nov 12 (Box 5)
  - Simpson, Mary Charlotte Mair (Senior) (Mrs. C. T. Simpson), 1873 Mar 2 (Box 5)
  - [Spencer, Herbert?] 1820-1903, 1871 Sep 16 (Box 5)
  - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher), 1811-1896
    - copy, 1869 Dec 10 (Box 5)
      Tinker 954
    - fragment; copy, [1872 Oct?] (Box 5)
      Tinker 955
    - copy, 1879 Apr 10 (Box 5)
      Tinker 956
  - Taylor, Clementia (Doughty) (Mrs. Peter A. Taylor), 1872 Apr 24 (Box 5)
  - Thompson, Catharine (Paget) (Mrs. Henry Lewis Thompson), 1877 May 17 (Box 5)
  - The Times, 1859 Apr 15 (Box 5)
    copy in an unidentified hand; Accompanied by a copy in an unidentified hand of GHL's letter to J. R. Quirk, 19 August 1859, and a clipping about Liggins signed "L"
  - Tollemache, Marguerite Home (Purvis) 1817-1896 (Mrs. William Augustus Tollemache), [1872] May 21 (Box 5)
  - Trübner, Nicolaus, 1817-1884
    - ----, 1871 Nov 13 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1877 May 27 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1879 Jul 30 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1879 Nov [9?] (Box 5)
  - Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps) (Mrs. H.D. Ward)
    - copy, 1875 Aug 13 (Box 5)
    - copy, 1876 Dec 16 (Box 5)
    - copy, 1877 Nov 13 (Box 5)
    - copy, 1879 Apr 10 (Box 5)
      See: letters by Mrs. Ward to GE
  - Watts, Francis, [1842] Apr 11 (Box 5)
  - Watts, George Frederick, 1870 Jan 11 (Box 5)
  - [Zimmerman, Agnes?], 1866 Oct 23 (Box 5)
- Section II. Letters by GEORGE HENRY LEWES to:, [1870?]
  - Signature on quotation from T. Chalmers, [1870?] (Box 5)
  - Unidentified recipient
    - Saturday, n.d. (Box 5)
    - I have given up..., n.d. (Box 5)
    - ----, 1867 Oct 9 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1872 Nov 29 (Box 5)
  - Appleton, Charles Edward Cutts Birch, [1871 Feb 6] (Box 5)
  - Baily, Mr., n.d. (Box 5)
    Wednesday, watermark 1865
  - Baudissin, Ida, Countess von, 1814-1888, [1869 Feb 4] (Box 5)
  - Benzon, Elizabeth Lehmann
    - Tuesday, n.d. (Box 5)
      Accompanied by a sonnet to Mrs. Benzon, 17 May 1872
  - Blackie, John Stuart, 1809-1895, 1855 Dec 19 (Box 5)
  - Blackwood, John, 1818-1879, [1859 Aug 3?]
    - ----, 1861 Mar 6 (Box 5)
  - Blackwood, Messrs. William & Sons, 1866 Apr 25 (Box 5)
  - Bodichon, Barbara Leigh (Smith), 1827-1891 (Mme. Eugène Bodichon)
    - Wednesday, [1863 Sep 30] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1869 Jun 16] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1869 Jul 6] (Box 5)
    - Saturday, [1870 May 21] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1870 Dec 19] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1871 Jan 6] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1871 Dec 12] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1875 Aug 13] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1876 Jun 6 (Box 5)
    - Postcard, 1877 Mar 28 (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1877 May 4] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1877 May 18] (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, [1877 Nov 27] (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1878 Jan 31] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1878 Feb 27] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1878 Jun 5] (Box 5)
    - Postcard, 1878 Nov 1 (Box 5)
  - Bohn, Henry George, 1796-1884
    - unsigned draft, 1856 Jun 8 (Box 5)
    - draft, 1856 Jun 15 (Box 5)
  - Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872, [1866] Friday (Box 5)
  - Bracebridge, Charles Holte, 1799-1872
    - MS copy in GE's hand, [1859 Sep 19] (Box 5)
    - MS copy in an unidentified hand, 1859 Sep 19 (Box 5)
    - MS copy in an unidentified hand, 1859 Sep 29 (Box 5)
    - Draft, 1859 Oct 7 (Box 5)
  - Bray, Caroline (Hennell), 1814-1905, [1863 Feb?]
    - ----, [1875 May 11] (Box 5)
  - Bray, Charles, 1811-1884
    - ----, [1852 Jun?] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1854 Jun 25] (Box 5)
    - On verso of letter from GE, [1859 Jun 24] (Box 5)
    - to Charles Bray Thursday, [1859 Jun 30] (Box 5)
    - Postscript added to letter, [1859 Sep 28] (Box 5)
    - from GE to Charles Bray Friday, [1859 Sep 30?] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1859 Oct 3] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1860 Mar 23] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1867] (Box 5)
  - Browning, Oscar, [1867 Jul]
    - postcard, 1875 Dec 13 (Box 5)
  - Buchheim, Carl Adolf, 1875 Oct 15 (Box 5)
  - [Busk, George (1807-1886)], [1868 Nov] (Box 5)
  - Chapman, John, 1821-1894, [1854 Jan 31?] (Box 5)
  - Cohn, Albert
    - Friday, [1873 Dec 10] (Box 5)
  - Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1832-1907
    - Wednesday, [186?] (Box 5)
    - Saturday, [1866 Nov] (Box 5)
  - Craik, George Lillie, 1837-1905
    - Thursday, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Cracroft, Bernard
    - Empty envelope postmarked, 1873 Nov 25 (Box 5)
  - Cross, the Misses, [1877] Jul 31 (Box 5)
  - Cross, Anna (Chalmers) (Mrs. William Cross)
    - Monday, [1871 Jul 24] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1871 Oct 21 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1872 Jun 25 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1872 Dec 29 (Box 5)
    - Saturday, [1872 Apr 27] (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1875 Jan 13] (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, [1877 Mar 20] (Box 5)
    - Christmas Eve, 1877 Dec 24 (Box 5)
  - Cross, John Walter
    - Wednesday, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1873] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1873 Jan 17 (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1873 Jan 19] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1873 Apr 18] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1873 May 26] (Box 5)
    - Post card, 1874 Feb 21 (Box 5)
    - Early August, [1874] (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, [1874 Oct 27] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1875 Sep 17] (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1877 Feb 22] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1877 Mar 5] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1877 Mar 16] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1877 Jun 10] (Box 5)
  - Dennis, John, 1866 May 10 (Box 5)
  - Dew-Smith, A.G., n.d. (Box 5)
  - Empson, William, 1791-1852, [1849] (Box 5)
  - Espinasse, Francis, 1861 Aug 27 (Box 5)
  - Goethe, Ottilie von, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Gordon, G.H., [1866] (Box 5)
    OSBORN FILES
  - Hamilton and Company
    - postcard, 1877 Apr 24 (Box 5)
  - Hennell, Sara Sophia, [1859 Apr 15]
    - with postscript by GE, 1860 Jul 9 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 Sep 5 (Box 5)
  - Hickson, William Edward
    - I am going to Paris..., n.d. (Box 5)
    - The following undated letters are endorsed and dated by Hickson:, 1843 Sep 4 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1843 Nov 1 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1843 Dec 20 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1843 Dec 22 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1844 Jan 12 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1844 Aug 12 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1844 Sep (Box 5)
    - ----, 1845 Mar 22 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1847 Sep 12 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1847 Nov 8 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1847 Dec 6 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1848 Mar 5 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1849 Jul 4 (Box 5)
  - Holyoake, George Jacob, 1817-1906, 1875 Aug 1 (Box 5)
  - Hullah, John Pyke, [1865 Aug 5] (Box 5)
  - Huth, Mrs. Henry
    - Thursday, [1876] (Box 5)
  - Hutton, J, No year May 5 (Box 5)
  - Kean, Charles John, [1852] Oct 18 (Box 5)
  - Kemble, John M., [1844?] Mar 23 (Box 5)
  - Kestner, Georg Heinrich Friedrich Wilhelm, 1863 May 20 (Box 5)
    Photostat of the original in the University Library, Leipzig
  - Lehmann, Nina (Chambers) (Mrs. Frederick Lehmalm)
    - ----, [1865 Jan] (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1867 May?] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1876 May 8] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1877 Feb 26] (Box 5)
  - Lewes, Charles, Thornton and Herbert; Lewes, Charles Lee, 1842-1891; Lewes, Thornton Arnott, 1844-1869; Lewes, Herbert Arthur, 1846-1875
    The letters so indicated are addressed to his three sons; the remainder are addressed to Charles Lee Lewes.
    - to his sons, 1854 Sep 27 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1857 Apr 15 (Box 5)
    - to his sons, 1857 Jun 18 (Box 5)
    - ----, [1857] Nov 29 (Box 5)
    - to his sons, 1858 Mar 24 (Box 5)
    - ----, [1858] Apr 20 (Box 5)
    - to his sons, 1858 Jul 20 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1858 Nov 20 (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1859 Jul 7] (Box 5)
    - Monday night. to his sons, [1859 Jul 11] (Box 5)
    - to his sons, 1859 Nov 10 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1860 Mar 17 (Box 5)
    - to his sons, 1860 May 6 (Box 5)
    - ----, [1860] May 30 (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1861 Apr 21] (Box 5)
    - With postscript by GE, 1861 May 5 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1862 May 21 (Box 5)
    - ----, [1862 Sep 5?] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1862 Sep 8] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1863] Feb 24 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 Mar 18 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 May 11 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 May 20 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 May 26 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1864 Jun 5 (Box 5)
    - With note by CLL to his aunt Mrs. Edward Lewes, [1864 Sep 18] (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1864 Sep 28] (Box 5)
    - Postscript to letter of March 28 addressed to Mrs. John Willim, 1870 Mar 29 (Box 5)
  - Lewes, Charles and Gertrude; Lewes, Charles Lee; Lewes, Gertrude (Hill)
    The letters addressed to Mr. and Mrs. Charles Lee Lewes are marked by an asterisk (_). The remainder are addressed to Charles Lee Lewes
    - Saturday, _[1865 Mar 29] (Box 5)
    - Postscript to letter addressed, _1866 Jun 13 (Box 5)
    - to Mrs. John Willim ----, _1866 Jun 22 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1866 Jul 1 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1866 Jul 15 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Jan 3 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Jan 11 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Jan 26 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Feb 18 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Feb 27 (Box 5)
    - ----, _[1867] May 2 (Box 5)
    - ----, _1867 Aug 8 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1867 Sep 13 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1867 Sep 23 (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, _[1869 May 19] (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1869 Nov 2] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1870 Apr 23 (Box 5)
    - Saturday, [1870 May 7] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1870 May 17 (Box 5)
    - With a note by CLL to his grand-, 1870 Jul 3 (Box 5)
    - mother, Mrs. John Willim Tuesday, [1870 Jul 19] (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1870 Aug 25] (Box 5)
    - ----, _1870 Dec 25 (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1871 Apr 26] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1871 May 5 (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1871 May 26] (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1871 Jun 7] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1871 Jun 9] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1871 Aug 4] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1871 Aug 27] (Box 5)
    - Monday, [1871 Aug 28] (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1872 Jun 13] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1872] Jun 19 (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1872 Jun 23] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1872 Jun 30] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1872] Aug 9 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1872 Oct 10 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1873 Jul 4 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1873 Aug 8 (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1874 Jun 18] (Box 5)
    - ----, 1874 Jul 1 (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1874 Aug 16] (Box 5)
    - Thursday, [1875 Jun 24] (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1875 Jul 11] (Box 5)
    - Saturday-Sunday, [1875 Aug 7-8] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1875 Sep] 23 (Box 5)
    - Sunday, [1876 Jun] 25 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1876 Jul 6 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1876 Jul 24 (Box 5)
    - ----, 1876 Aug 19 (Box 5)
    - ----, [1878] Jul 3 (Box 5)
    - Wednesday, [1878 Jul 10] (Box 5)
    - ----, [1878 Aug 26] (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, [1878 Sep 3 or10?] (Box 5)
    - Friday, [1878 Sep 6] (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, [1878 Oct 15] (Box 5)
  - Liebreich, Richard
    - Monday (Box 5)
  - Lindau, Paul, 1839-1919, 1875 Sep 23 (Box 5)
  - Main, Alexander, 1841-1918, 1875 Jul 22
    - ----, 1871 Dec 20 (Box 5)
  - [Mathews, Charles James, 1803-1878]
    - Thursday, 1854 [Jan?] (Box 6)
  - Mitchell, Dr. Silas Weir, 1829-1914, 1862 Aug 30 (Box 6)
  - Moscheles, Mrs. Felix, 1877 Apr 12 (Box 6)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot
    - Postcard, 1873 Apr 16 (Box 6)
  - Nutt, David
    - Thursday, [1857] (Box 6)
    - ----, 1857 Jul 7 (Box 6)
  - Osgood, J.R. and Sons, 1875 May 24 (Box 6)
  - Owen, Sir Richard, [1852?]
    - ----, 1862 Jun 3 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1867 Oct 4 (Box 6)
  - [Parker, John William], [1847 Apr or May] (Box 6)
  - Pigott, Edward Frederick Smyth, 1858 Jun 27
    - with postscript to GE, 1858 Jul 20 (Box 6)
  - Quirk, James R.
    - Partial copy in an unidentified, 1859 Aug 19 (Box 6)
    - hand (Box 6)
  - Reynolds, Frances (Mrs. John Russell), 1874 Jan 11 (Box 6)
  - Reynolds, Sir John Russell, Bart., 1828-1896
    - With env. & port. of GHL, [1870] Jul 8 (Box 6)
  - Rodgers, Guy (Box 6)
    See: Smith, George Barnett
  - Roslyn, Guy (Box 6)
  - Scribner, Messrs. and Co., [1866?] Aug 21 (Box 6)
  - Simpson, George
    - Monday, [1875 Dec 6] (Box 6)
  - Smith, George Barnett, 1841-1899, 1872 Dec 8
    - (Guy Roslyn was the pseudonym of George Barnett Smith) Rodgers was GHL's misreading of Roslyn, [1877] Nov 15 (Box 6)
    - Tinker 996 (Box 6)
  - Stahr, Adolf, 1855 Nov 12 (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Sir Henry, [1878 Feb]
    - ----, [1878 Jun 12?] (Box 6)
  - Towle, George M.
    - Monday, [1866] (Box 6)
  - Trübner, Nicolaus
    - ----, 1867 May 29 (Box 6)
    - Thursday, [1873 Feb 20] (Box 6)
    - to Trübner's manager, [1878] Apr 19 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1878 Jun 30 (Box 6)
  - Trübner, Mrs. Nicolaus, 1873 Mar 3 (Box 6)
  - Tugwell, George (11 ALS), 1858-61, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Webster Beniamin Nottingham, 1797-1882, [1854] (Box 6)
  - White, William Hale
    - Tuesday, [1876 May 9] (Box 6)
  - Willim, Elizabeth (Ashweek) Lewes (Mrs. John Willim)
    - Postscript to Mr. and Mrs. C.L. Lewes, 1866 Jun 13 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1867 Feb 5 (Box 6)
    - Postscript, dated March 29, to C.L. Lewes, 1870 Mar 28 (Box 6)
- Section III. Letters to/about GEORGE ELIOT & GEORGE HENRY LEWES
  - Anonymous letters to GE:
    - If to feel for you..., n.d. (Box 6)
    - ----, [1859?] (Box 6)
    - ----, 1868 Jul 31 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1872 Jun 4 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1876 May 31 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1876 Aug 31 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1878] Dec 4 (Box 6)
    - Signed "Dolores", in German, [1879] (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 Jan 19 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 May 30 (Box 6)
  - Anonymous letters to GHL:
    - I have been trying to read and comprehend your work..., [1874?] (Box 6)
  - Abbott, Edwin Abbott, 1838-1926
    - to GE, 1876 Sep 22 (Box 6)
  - Acton, John Emerich Edward Dalberg, 1st baron, 1834-1902
    to John Walter Cross
    Tinker 957
    - Don't forget that we..., n.d. (Box 6)
    - Easter Monday (Box 6)
    - ----, 1881 Jan 25 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1881 Feb 9 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1881?] Nov 22 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1882?] Feb 6 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1883 Jun 4 (Box 6)
    - I am sure you forgive me, [1883?] (Box 6)
    - Monday, [1883?] (Box 6)
    - ----, [1883?] Dec 2 (Box 6)
    - I have promised Dick, [1883?] (Box 6)
    - ----, [1883?] Dec 21 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1883?] Dec 27 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1884 Jan 5 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Feb 6 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Feb 8 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Apr 24 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 20 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Oct 22 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1884 Nov 2 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Nov 11 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1884 Nov 12 (Box 6)
    - Friday morning. I have an appointment..., [1884] (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Nov 27 (Box 6)
    - I came up yesterday..., [1884 Dec 4] (Box 6)
    - ----, [1884] Dec 5 (Box 6)
    - I am afraid you will find..., [1884 Dec] (Box 6)
    - ----, [1885] Jan 3 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1885] Jan 6 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1885] Mar 1 (Box 6)
  - Adams, Robert Dudley, 1829-
    - to GE, 1876 Jun 1 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 Oct 6 (Box 6)
  - Adler, Hermann, 1839-1911
    - to GE, 1876 Jun 23 (Box 6)
  - Aitchison, George
    - to GE, 1879 Dec 6 (Box 6)
  - Allbutt, Sir Thomas Clifford, 1836-1925
    to GE
    - Christmas, 1871 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 Jan 19 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 Feb 26 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1879 Apr 6 (Box 6)
  - Allen, Henry E.
    - to Richard Quain, 1879 Apr 21 (Box 6)
  - Allingham, Helen (Paterson)
    - to Elinor Ouvry, n.d. (Box 6)
    - ----, [1925?] Jun 18 (Box 6)
    - ----, [1925?] Jun 23 (Box 6)
    - ----, 1926 Jul 1 (Box 6)
  - Asher, David
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 6)
  - Bain, Alexander, 1818-1903
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 28 (Box 6)
    - to GHL, 1875 Mar 5 (Box 6)
  - Bairdner, W.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 7 (Box 6)
  - Barclay, Martha (Jackson), (Mrs. Henry Barclay)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1884 Jun 3 (Box 6)
  - Barrett-Lennard, M.
    - Monday, [187-] (Box 6)
  - Bates, Charlotte Fiske, 1838-
    - to GE, 1880 Jan 1 (Box 6)
  - Bayne, Peter, 1830-1896
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 6)
  - Beesly, Edward Spencer, 1831-1915
    - to GE, 1868 Nov 16
      - ----, 1869 May 20 (Box 6)
      - ----, 1870 Jun 10 (Box 6)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 6)
      - ----, 1880 May 8 (Box 6)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 4 (Box 6)
  - Beesly, Emily (Crompton) (Mrs. Edward Spencer Beesly)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 3 (Box 6)
  - Bell, Mrs. ("Nursie")
    - to GE, 1860 Jun 18 (Box 6)
  - Bell, James
    - to GE, 1871 Nov 18 (Box 6)
  - Belloc, Elizabeth [Bessie] Rayner (Parkes) (Mrs. Louis Belloc) 1829-1925
    - to GE, 1859 Aug 17 (Box 6)
  - Benisch, Abraham
    - to GE, 1876 Dec 15 (Box 6)
  - Benson, Robert H.
    - to GE, 1880 Apr 14 (Box 6)
  - Bishop, J
    - to GE, 1880 Feb 10 (Box 6)
      Verses, "Impromptu. After reading Silas Marner." on p. [2-4].
  - Blackie, John Stuart, 1809-1895
    - to GE, [1859] Dec 26 (Box 7)
  - Blackwood, G.W. and J.H.
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1926 Feb 19 (Box 7)
    - ----, 1927 Nov 14 (Box 7)
  - Blackwood, John, 1818-1879
    - to GE, 1860 Mar 22
      - ----, 1878 Sep 29 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 1 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 7)
    - to GHL, 1858 Nov 15
      - ----, 1872 Dec 21 (Box 7)
      - Tinker 958 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1877 Oct 25 (Box 7)
    - to Alexander Main, 1873 Nov 13 (Box 7)
      A copy [in the hand of George Simpson?]
  - Blackwood, William, 1810-1861
    - to GE, 1860 May 23 (Box 7)
  - Blackwood, William, 1836-1912
    - to GE, 1880 Jan 12 (Box 7)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1881 Jan 8 (Box 7)
      (photocopy)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1886 Feb 5 (Box 7)
    - to G.H. Lewes, 1866 Apr 24 (Box 7)
  - Bodichon, Barbara Leigh (Smith), 1827-1891 (Mme. Eugène Bodichon)
    - to GE, 1856 Jan 14
      - ----, 1856 Nov 21-Dec 8 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1858] Dec 2 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Apr?] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Apr 26 (Box 7)
      - Tinker 961 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Jun 28] (Box 7)
      - Tinker 962 (Box 7)
      - Aunt Julia does nothing..., [1859 Jun?] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Jun 30-Jul 1 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Jul 3] (Box 7)
      - Wednesday. I am going to Wimbeldon..., [1859 Jul] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Jul 25 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Aug 10 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Aug 26 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Aug 28] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Sep 28 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Nov 27 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] Dec 25 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1860] Jun 13 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1860 Dec 22 (Box 7)
      - Sunday. I hope you received..., [1863 Jul] (Box 7)
      - Enclosing 8 pages copied from Elizabeth Malleson's letters on Romola (lacks the end), 1867 Jan 11 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1867 Nov?-Dec 16 (Box 7)
      - I have read your new book..., [1871 Dec] (Box 7)
      - Friday. I have had some qualms..., [1873 Jan?] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1880] May 8 (Box 7)
      - Tinker 963 (Box 7)
    - to C.L. Lewes, [1880 May] (Box 7)
  - Copy in an unidentified hand of a portion of a letter [to her?] describing a visit with GE, 1879 Jun 22 (Box 7)
    Three pen and ink sketches of Elizabeth [Bessie] Rayner (Parkes) Belloc
  - Bohn, Henry George, 1796-1884
    - to GHL, 1856 Jun 3 (Box 7)
    - endorsed by GE, 1856 Jun 7 (Box 7)
    - ----, 1856 Jun 13 (Box 7)
    - ----, 1856 Jun 18 (Box 7)
  - Bond, Sir Edward Augustus, 1815-1898
    - to GE, 1874 Apr 9 (Box 7)
  - Bottrill, W. Evans
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 7)
  - Bowen, Charles Synge Christopher, 1st baron
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 4 (Box 7)
    - to J.W. Cross
      - In the important passage..., [1885] (Box 7)
      - I am delighted with the success..., [1885] (Box 7)
      - Tinker 960 (Box 7)
  - Bracebridge, Charles Holte, 1799-1872
    - to Charles Bray, [1859] Jul 3
      - ----, [1859] Sep 12 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Sep 13 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Sep 17 (Box 7)
      - I have returned the paper..., 1859 Sep 24 (Box 7)
      - A ship you see last week..., 1859 Sep 24 (Box 7)
      - With a copy of his letter to GHL, [1859 Oct 2] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859] (Box 7)
      - ----, [1860 Jul 15?] (Box 7)
    - to GE, 1859 Oct 10 (Box 7)
    - to GHL, [1859] Sep 26
      - ----, 1859 Oct 1 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Oct 4 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Oct 9 (Box 7)
  - Bray, Caroline (Hennell), 1814-1905
    - to Elizabeth Rebecca (Brabant) Hennell Call, 1844 Jul 28 (Box 7)
      Tinker 964
    - to GE, [1859] Jun 25
      - ----, [1859] Jul 24 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1863] Aug 31 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1873] Mar 21 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1873] Mar 23 (Box 7)
    - to Sara Sophia Hennell, 1845 Mar 30
      Tinker 965
      - ----, [1845 Aug] (Box 7)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1890 Mar 28 (Box 7)
  - Bray, Charles, 1811-1884
    - to C.H. Bracebridge, 1860 Jul 14 (Box 7)
      Draft. Accompanied by Frederick Temple's judgment in the case of Craddock vs. Bray, 12 July 1860.
    - to GE, 1855 Oct 13
      - ----, [1859 Jun 26] (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Jul 8 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Jul 18 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Aug 14 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Sep 18 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1859 Sep 20 (Box 7)
      - ----, [1859 Sep 26] (Box 7)
      - ----, 1874 May 18 (Box 7)
  - Bray-Hennell Extracts, all in the hand of Sara Sophia Hennell:
    - 1. Extracts from the letters of Sara Hennell, Mary Hennell, and Caroline Hennell Bray concerning GE., 1842-1849 (Box 7)
      Tinker 993
    - 2. Extracts of "quotable passages" from the letters of GE to Maria Lewis, John Sibree, and Mary Sibree Cash. (Box 7)
      Tinker 992
    - 3. Account of an incident in the childhood of GE, told by Miss Shaw. (Box 7)
  - Brewster, Margaret Maria
    - to GE, 1859 Oct 5 (Box 7)
  - Bridges, John Henry, 1832-1906
    - to GE, [1859] Sep 11 (Box 7)
  - British Museum (by Robin Flower)
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1939 Jun 13 (Box 7)
      On verso: List of GHL's manuscripts sold to Yale
  - Brock, T.D.C. (wife of the gardener at Witley)
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 6 (Box 7)
  - Broune, William Brockden
    - to GE, 1879 Dec 23 (Box 7)
  - Brown, George Dransfield
    - to GE, 1872 Dec 4 (Box 7)
  - Brown, Dr. John, 1810-188Z
    - to John Blackwood, [1859] Feb 16 (Box 7)
  - Browning, Oscar, 1837-1923
    - to an unidentified recipient, 1890 Nov 11 (Box 7)
      About Rajon's etching of GE
    - to GE, 1867 Jul 22
      - ----, 1868 May 24 (Box 7)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1890 Mar 18
      - ----, 1890 Apr 1 (Box 7)
  - Bruce, John G.
    - to GE, 1880 Apr 9 (Box 7)
  - Bryce, James Bryce, viscount, 1838-1922
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] May 27 (Box 7)
    - ----, [1885] Mar 21 (Box 7)
    - ----, [1885] Apr 22 (Box 7)
      Tinker 966
  - Buchanan, Robert, 1841-1901
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 9 (Box 7)
    - to GHL, 1864 Jun 30